In classical embryology, we talk about three
在经典胚胎学中，我们谈论三种
tissues.
组织。
Ecto, endo, meso.
外胚层、内胚层、中胚层。
In histology, we talk about two tissues,
在组织学中，我们谈论两种组织，
and we could summarize these histological tissues into two main types of tissues.
我们可以将这些组织学组织概括为两大类组织。
Epithelial tissues of ectodermal origin,
源自外胚层的上皮组织，
epithelial tissues of endodermal origin,
源自内胚层的上皮组织，
In other words, epithelial tissues of neurological origin,
换句话说，源自神经系统的上皮组织，
epithelial tissues of digestive origin, or
源自消化系统的上皮组织，或者
here, connective tissues, of mesodermal origin.
这里，源自中胚层的结缔组织。
I have added here a layer that begins to enter
我在这里添加了一层，它开始进入
into the Blechmit process, two qualities of tissue on a plane of
Blechmit 的过程，在运动平面上有两种组织品质，
movement, and it joins...
它与……
In fact, a bit of histology.
实际上，有点像组织学。
Finally, he says, I have boundary tissue,
最后，他说，我有边界组织，
or what he calls frontier tissue,
或者他称之为边界组织，
or I have interior tissue,
或者我有内部组织，
what he calls connective tissue.
他称之为结缔组织。
He says, boundary tissue is always ectoderm and endoderm,
他说，边界组织总是外胚层和内胚层，
and interior tissue is always mesoderm.
而内部组织总是中胚层。
When I use red, in general,
当我使用红色时，通常，
I will always draw what is representative of the endoderm.
我总是会画出代表内胚层的东西。
or more specifically of the
或者更具体地说，是消化
digestive system. When I use
系统。当我使用
blue,
蓝色时，
I will essentially use the
我主要会使用
ectodermal tissue. When I use
外胚层组织。当我主要使用
essentially mesodermal,
中胚层组织时，
which comes and which I study,
它出现并被我研究，
and I see, oh, I'm on an artery.
我看到，哦，我正在研究一条动脉。
Well, for me,
那么，我，
in my head, it immediately goes,
在我的脑海中，它立刻就是，
it's an artery, a mesoderm,
这是一条动脉，一个中胚层，
interior tissue. I know
内部组织。我知道
where I am in the system.
我在系统中的位置。
So I recognize a dynamic,
所以我识别出一种动力，
already, it allows me to orient myself.
这已经让我能够定位自己。
This is the link between histology,
这是组织学、
embryology
胚胎学
and biodynamic embryology.
和生物动力胚胎学之间的联系。
Well, it's a bit of a representation
嗯，这有点像
of the tissue
外胚层
ectodermal, epithelial.
上皮组织。
It's the ectoderm, meaning
这是外胚层，也就是说
it's a tissue
它是一种组织
that is concentrated
它集中在
between a liquid
液体和
and an interior tissue.
内部组织之间。
Here, I have the sea, and
这里，我有大海，
in the center, between the two, I have an interior tissue, and
在中间，两者之间，我有一个内部组织，
below, I have the Mediterranean,
在下面，我有地中海，
a mesodermal tissue, an endodermal tissue, also concentrated,
中胚层组织，内胚层组织，也集中在一起，
we often see near
我们经常在
the sea, like that, you see, a concentration. And so here, what
海边看到，就像这样，你看到，一个集中。所以这里，我们看到了什么？
do we see? It will
它将
explain to us the characteristics of these tissues, that the boundary tissue, excuse me,
向我们解释这些组织的特征，即组织，抱歉，边界组织
is always located between what we call the fluid and
总是位于我们所说的液体和
the interior tissue. If we
内部组织之间。如果我们
observe the eardrum, it is made of three tissues. It is made of ectodermal tissue, on
观察鼓膜，它由三种组织构成。它由外胚层组织构成，在
the outside,
外部，
inside, it is made of tissue.
在内部，它由组织构成。
The endodermal tissue, and in the middle, it is made of
内胚层组织，在中间，它由
mesodermal tissue.
中胚层组织构成。
The frontier tissue, therefore the boundary tissue,
边界组织，也就是限制组织，
is always dependent on the interior tissue.
总是依赖于内部组织。
In other words, epithelial tissue is always
换句话说，上皮组织总是
dependent on connective tissue.
依赖于结缔组织。
because the vessels and nourishment come from the interior
因为血管和营养来自
tissue
内部组织
and is distributed in the frontier tissue.
并分布到边界组织中。
So, in other words, it is the mesodermal tissue
所以，换句话说，是中胚层组织
that contains the trophic information for growth and maintenance
包含了营养、生长和维持
of growth.
生长的信息。
Much more serious than here.
比这里严重得多。
There is no congestion in the boundary tissue.
边界组织中不存在充血。
but that there can be phases of congestion
但内部组织中可能存在充血阶段。
in the interior tissue.
在内部组织中。
Take these tissues and you realize
拿起这些组织，你会发现
that there is a dried area.
有一个干燥的区域。
You must rehydrate, reopen, reconnect.
你必须重新补水，重新打开，重新连接。
It can be congestion
这可能是一种充血
or a drying phase.
或干燥阶段。
And in life, that's how it happens.
在生活中，事情就是这样。
If you have dryness,
如果你有干燥，
the tissue is completely dry.
组织完全干燥。
If it rains too much, you have phases of congestion.
如果它太多，你就会有充血阶段。
And you also have natural phases of congestion.
你也有自然的充血阶段。
A woman has natural congestions.
女性有自然的充血。
every month, she has uterine congestion
每个月，她都会有子宫充血
which is a cleansing
这是一种清洁
because she is ready to welcome life
因为她准备好迎接生命
and so what happens, if she cannot welcome
那么会发生什么，如果她不能迎接
well, the entire glandular system
那么整个腺体系统
shrinks, eliminates itself
会收缩，消除
and she moves on to another...
她会转向另一个...
So this corresponds a bit to the campaign
所以这有点像乡村
it means that this tissue here
这意味着这里的组织
it will give the whole system
它将形成整个系统
that is to say
也就是说
all my vessels
我所有的血管
all my arteries, all my veins
我所有的动脉，我所有的静脉
my whole system
我所有的系统
It will also give the entire skeletal, musculo-
它还将形成整个骨骼系统，肌肉
skeletal system, bones, membranes, peritoneums, in the
-骨骼系统，骨骼，膜，腹膜，在
cranium you will call them reciprocal tension membranes.
颅骨中，你将称之为相互张力膜。
The entire circulatory system, the entire urogenital system and the entire
整个循环系统，整个泌尿生殖系统和所有
support system, it is mesodermal tissue or in other
支持系统，它是中胚层组织，或者换句话说
words it is mesodermal tissue.
它是中胚层组织。
we find a great variety of forms in the boundary tissue,
我们在边界组织中发现了各种各样的形式，
these are surface growths, there is no congestion phase
它们是表面生长，没有充血阶段
and there are
而且有
many cells. It is always dependent on the interior tissue,
很多细胞。它总是依赖于内部组织，
whereas
而
the interior tissue, it is between the two tissues. Let's assume
内部组织，它位于两个组织之间。假设
now
现在
that I receive a good blow to the face.
我脸上挨了一记重击。
I fart, I make a connection, you see, the pressure is made,
我放屁，我遇到，你看，压力产生了，
and I remove the interior tissue.
我移除了内部组织。
What do I have in my camp?
我的阵营里有什么？
There is no more liquid.
没有液体了。
There is no more liquid, I lose the interior tissue.
没有液体了，我失去了内部组织。
Okay?
好吗？
For example, two vessels meeting.
例如，两条血管相遇。
You see, the tissue, the tissue.
你看，组织，组织。
I lose my interior tissue, I have a corrosion field.
我失去了内部组织，我有一个腐蚀场。
In a very simplified way, I
非常简单地说，我
see that all the constituents of connective tissue are
看到结缔组织的所有成分都
summarized in these four major components.
总结在这四个主要组成部分中。
Now, if I take a tissue and
现在，如果我取一块组织，
I'm going to put a bone here, a muscle.
我将在这里放一块骨头，一块肌肉。
I'm going to compare them. In a bone, there are many cells. However,
我将它们进行比较。在骨头中，有很多细胞。但是，
I have little water or minerals.
我几乎没有水或矿物质。
And there, in the fibers, what will I have in a bone or collagen
那么，在纤维中，骨头或胶原蛋白中会有什么呢？
?
？
If I take a muscle, I have a few less cells,
如果我取一块肌肉，我的细胞会少一点，
I have a little more water.
我的水分会多一点。
At the matrix level, there is a change.
在基质层面，有一个变化。
At the fiber level, I have more elastic.
在纤维层面，我有更多的弹性。
Now, if we go a little further,
现在，如果我们再深入一点，
we have what are called glycosaminoglycans.
我们有所谓的糖胺聚糖。
I enter into this matrix process.
我进入了这个基质过程。
And what do I observe?
我发现了什么？
That I either have a structure that is permeable,
我有一个渗透性结构，
that is to say, rather depolymerized,
也就是说，它更倾向于解聚，
or I have a structure that is rather...
或者我有一个更倾向于...
dense, which is therefore dense, which is hard, where I have
致密的，因此是致密的，坚硬的，我有一个
what is called a polymerized structure.
我们称之为聚合的结构。
What is the densest structure in the body?
身体中最致密的结构是什么？
The dense one.
致密的。
We will say the ligaments, the ligaments, then
我们会说韧带，韧带，然后
we will say the tendons.
我们会说肌腱。
And then we'll put the blood up to here.
然后我们把血液放在这里。
We'll go that far.
我们到此为止。
We can put all the mesodermal type structures here.
我们可以把所有中胚层类型的结构放在这里。
And I simply observe that it is either permeable or
我只是发现它要么是可渗透的，要么是
it is viscous.
粘稠的。
And if I go that way, I go towards something fluid.
如果我往这边走，我走向流体的东西。
That way, what am I going towards?
往这边走，我走向什么？
constraints
限制
the observation of teeth
牙齿观察
the observation of occlusion
对咬合的观察
gives you
会给你
the perfect image
完美的图像
of the constraints
关于限制
that are found at the level of the sphenobasilar symphysis
位于蝶枕结合处
and we will see
我们会看到
that this sphenobasilar symphysis
这个蝶枕结合处
in embryology
在胚胎学中
it's a key
是一个关键
for the body
对于身体
it's as if
就好像
I could call it the zero point
我可以称之为零点
a point
一个点
neutral that receives
中立的，接收
all the information of the body
身体的所有信息
whether on the vascular level
无论是血管方面
lymphatic
淋巴方面
whether on the neurological level
无论是神经方面
digestive
消化方面
tension membrane etc.
张力膜等等
the sphenobasilar symphysis is aware
蝶枕结合处都知道
of everything that happens
所有发生的事情
and the teeth will always
牙齿总是会
manage as best they can
尽力而为
If they have to grind their teeth or do anything
如果需要磨牙或做任何事情
to give freedom
为了获得自由
at those levels.
在这些层面上。
And the base of the teeth, the occlusion,
牙齿的基础，咬合，
the teeth, they are posture sensors.
牙齿，它们是姿势感受器。
It means
这意味着
that it is a very important relationship
牙齿之间存在着非常重要的关系
between the teeth and the notochord.
牙齿和脊索之间。
Or more precisely,
或者更准确地说，
it is a very important relationship
牙齿之间存在着非常重要的关系
between the teeth
牙齿
and the entire vertebral axis.
和整个脊柱轴。
Or in other words,
换句话说，
the teeth can
牙齿可以
can disturb the statics.
扰乱静态。
In other words, a herniated disc can be treated by rebalancing the occlusion.
换句话说，通过重新平衡咬合可以治疗椎间盘突出。
The teeth, they are the ones that can take the constraints,
牙齿，它们能够承受压力，
they are the ones that carry the karmic burden of your life.
它们承载着你生命中的业力负担。
Health is a balance, we talked about it, in
健康是一种平衡，我们已经谈过了，在这种
this dynamic.
动态中。
It is a harmony that will express a state of well-being.
这是一种和谐，它将表达一种良好的状态。
etc. Let's take a tendon. I have a tendon. Which,
等等。我们来拿一根肌腱。我有一根肌腱。它
if it is free in its good dynamic,
如果它在良好的动态中是自由的，
there is no problem, it is in its good network, it is in a good balance
就没有问题，它处于良好的网络中，它处于良好的平衡中，
between the
在
constraint and the fluids. It is in balance and in a fair
压力和液体之间。它处于平衡中，处于一种恰当的
exchange of trophic information,
营养信息交换中，
it receives. But now, it happens that there is an imbalance
它接收。但现在，发生了一个不平衡，
which can be internal.
这可能来自内部。
or an imbalance coming from outside due to a profession,
或者由于职业原因，外部导致的不平衡，
well, all of a sudden, the tendon loses its quality of place.
那么，突然之间，肌腱就失去了它的位置质量。
And what does it do? It has more constraints.
它做了什么？它承受了更多的压力。
And so, it goes that way.
所以，它就朝那个方向发展。
And so, what does it receive in its metabolism?
那么，它的新陈代谢接收到了什么？
A change of information.
信息的变化。
This will lead to what is called calcifying tendinitis.
这会导致我们所说的钙化性肌腱炎。
And what happens when I have calcifying tendinitis?
当我患有钙化性肌腱炎时，什么会离开？
The bone, I harden, you see, and
骨头，我变硬了，你看，然后
I catch here.
我在这里抓挠。
Because we will see in detail that the limbs are an expansion of a peritoneal sac,
因为我们将详细看到，四肢是腹膜囊的扩张，
pleurocardio-peritoneal, you see, in a specific movement.
胸膜心包腹膜，你看，在特定的运动中。
It will happen at the same time as this movement happens here, you see.
它将与这里的运动同时发生，你看。
The result of your sphere here, the elbow, the wrist, we will find it in the body like that.
你这里，肘部，手腕的球体的结果，我们会在身体中找到它。
I have hepatosis or I have a pulmonary deficit or something else, it can block
我患有肝病或者肺部或其他方面有缺陷，这可能会阻碍
my system
我的系统
of rotation here and express itself at a distance here. So sometimes what happens here
在这里旋转，并在这里远距离表达。所以有时这里发生的事情
can be the expression
可能是
of an imbalance that happens here. Through this study of embryology, it will give us
这里发生的不平衡的表达。通过对胚胎学的研究，这将给我们
what we
我们所说的
call the links and interactions of tissues. Allostasis is
组织之间的联系和相互作用。异稳态，它
the processes that allow
是允许
to maintain homeostasis.
保持稳态的过程。
to rebalance this, so it's all the processes and for that I need
重新平衡这一点，所以这是所有的过程，为此我需要
a magnetic force, I need an electricity, a voltage
一种磁力，我需要一种电，一种电压
we even measured, it's a Swiss biologist friend who measured on the
我们甚至测量过，是一位瑞士生物学家在
membrane the electrical forces in the glycocalyx that were expressed so
糖萼中的电场，它表达出来
on this
在这个
electrical network, it's enormous in fact that we're going to go into this perception, we're
电网络上，我们实际上将进入这种感知，
going to work with a microcrystalline field
我们将使用微晶场。
If we are going to go into this force of perception at the level of the embryo,
如果我们要进入胚胎层面的这种感知力，
we must refine certain notions here and certain notions here.
我们必须在这里和那里细化某些概念。
You will see that the touch is extremely gentle.
你会发现触感极其柔和。
When I touch someone, people tell me, it's very gentle.
当我触摸某人时，他们会说，这很柔和。
And at the same time, we feel that it's very global, if you will.
同时，你会觉得它非常整体。
Because I work on this microcrystalline field.
因为我正在处理这个微晶场。
We will see that the hand comes to rest in its formation on the heart.
我们会看到手在形成过程中会放在心脏上。
That your eyes...
你的眼睛...
rests on the heart
落在心上
and that your voice
和你的声音
and that the heart emits a rhythmic field
而心脏会发出一种有节奏的场
already on the 23rd day
早在第23天
very powerful
非常强大
which informs
它会传递信息
in a pulsatile way
以脉动的方式
you see
你明白吗
and in a rhythmic way
以有节奏的方式
and in an electrical way
以电的方式
your hands
你的手
it means that you are informed
这意味着你被告知
already by the rhythm of the heart
已经被心跳的节奏所告知
even in your gaze.
甚至在你的眼神中。
And it happens at the level of the thyroid.
这发生在甲状腺层面。
The thyroid comes from the tongue,
甲状腺，它来自舌头，
and the tongue is the bud of the heart.
而舌头是心脏的芽。
You see?
你明白吗？
It's when I speak, at 7 years old,
当我在7岁时说话时，
my sinus opens,
我的鼻窦打开了，
at the same time that my thyroid becomes completely active
同时我的甲状腺在振动层面变得完全活跃。
on the vibratory level.
在振动层面上。
You see?
你明白吗？
And that's why at 7, I can stand up for myself.
这就是为什么在7岁时，我能够面对。
I can start to defend myself with words.
我可以用我的
word. Before that,
话语来为自己辩护。在此之前，
I fought,
我打架，
children, they fight before. And then at some point,
孩子们之前会打架。然后到了某个时候，
they reach the age of reason.
他们有理智的年龄。
Hey, I can talk.
看，我能说话了。
Because all of a sudden, I receive my strength
因为突然间，我从中获得了力量
here, in words.
在这里，在文字中。
I can start to reason with my head.
我可以用我的头脑开始思考。
That's the song of the heart.
这就是心之歌。
That's what will be expressed.
这就是将要表达的。
it's a movement
这是一种运动
of the sphenoid
蝶骨的
in connection
与
with the upper maxilla.
上颌骨相连。
The occiput is fixed, the jaw
枕骨是固定的，下颌骨
remains fixed. This gives
保持固定。这会产生
a twisting movement.
扭转运动。
Look at the position of the teeth.
看看牙齿的位置。
We sometimes find
我们有时会
this kind of thing in patients.
在患者身上发现这种现象。
Cross-articulated.
交叉咬合。
Now, in the image of a
现在，在一个
What we call a side bending, look, at
我们称之为侧弯的图像中，看，在
the level of the occiput, look carefully, this time occiput, side bending, rotation,
枕骨的水平，仔细看，这次是枕骨，侧弯，旋转，
look what happens at the level of my sphenobasilar symphysis, look, you
看我的蝶枕结合处发生了什么，看，你
saw, look what happens at the level of the face, one eye smaller,
看到了吗，看脸部发生了什么，一只眼睛更
one eye larger, look, nasion, look at the position of the jaws.
小，一只眼睛更大，看，鼻骨，看颌骨的位置。
Look this time at the link between the upper maxilla and the lower maxilla.
这次看看上颌骨和下颌骨之间的联系。
Look at the image of the strains.
看看“strengs”的图像。
Cervical strains, upper, lower strains.
颈部“strengs”，上部“strengs”，下部“strengs”。
Look what happens at that level.
看看在这个层面上发生了什么。
Look at someone who has prognathism or retrognathism.
看看有下颌前突或下颌后缩的人。
This is the introduction.
这是介绍。
that we will put
我们将要放置的
in the future establishment
在未来建立
of the notochordal axis
脊索轴的过程中
with the future development of the sacrum
随着骶骨的未来发展
and the axis
以及
primitive cranio-sacral.
原始颅骶轴。
That is to say, when we touch
也就是说，当我们触摸
a sacrum, it has the history of all that.
骶骨时，它承载着所有这些历史。
And you will see that a sacrum
你会看到骶骨
is a base of the skull,
是颅骨的基底，
it makes no difference.
这没有任何区别。
It's the same thing.
它们是一样的。
It's the same tissue, it's just a...
它们是同一种组织，只是一个……
movement. We will see in development, the sacrum will be the mobile fulcrum
运动。我们将在发育中看到，骶骨将是活动的支点，
and the base of the
而颅骨
cranium will be the fulcrum. That's why the sacrum is at the base of cortical
底部将是支撑点。这就是为什么骶骨是皮层发育的基础。首先，当我谈到外胚层时，我指的是哪种组织？
development. Firstly, when I talk about ectoderm, what tissue am I talking about
皮层。首先，当我谈到外胚层时，我指的是哪种组织？
?
？
1,360. I will keep your notes if necessary. What tissue am I talking about when we talk about ectoderm,
1,360。如果需要，我会保留你的笔记。当我们谈到外胚层时，我指的是哪种组织？
I am talking about tissue? 1,360. Two limits. On a histological level,
我指的是组织？1,360。两个限制。从组织学角度来看，
what tissue am I talking about?
我指的是哪种组织？
Epithelial.
上皮组织。
And on a structural level,
从结构角度来看，
when I talk about ectodermal tissue,
当我谈到外胚层组织时，
I'm talking about your entire nervous system,
我指的是你们的整个神经系统，
central,
中枢神经系统，
peripheral,
周围神经系统，
and the skin around it.
以及周围的皮肤。
So this is viscerocranium.
所以，这是内脏颅。
This is neurocranium.
这是神经颅。
One is endodermal,
一个是内胚层，
the other is ectodermal.
另一个是外胚层。
When I talk to you about the viscerocranium,
当我谈到内脏颅时，
it's the face,
它是面部，
but it's up to here.
但它只到这里。
All of this is viscerocranium.
所有这些都是内脏颅。
I told you,
我告诉过你，
I remember, in the small table,
我记得在那个小表格里，
I said the interior tissue
我说过内部组织
and the boundary tissue.
和边界组织。
And I said
我说过
that one was always
一个总是
dependent on the other.
依赖于另一个。
So the boundary tissue
所以边界组织
is always dependent on the interior tissue.
总是依赖于内部组织。
In other words,
换句话说，
I cannot
我不能
talk about the development
谈论神经系统
nervous system, without its wrapping, which is
的发育，没有它的包裹，也就是
its mesodermal system, or in other
它的中胚层系统，或者换句话说，
words, which will be all the tension membranes, or in other words, which will be
它将是所有的张力膜，或者换句话说，它将是
the dura
硬脑膜，
mater, and its entire system around it.
以及它周围的所有系统。
I cannot talk about it, I cannot separate them in development.
我不能谈论它，我不能在发展中将它们分开。
Same thing, I cannot talk to you about the digestive tract.
同样，我不能向你谈论消化道，
without talking to you about the peritoneum.
而不谈论腹膜。
But the peritoneum is not endoderm, it is mesoderm.
但是腹膜不是内胚层，它是中胚层。
Okay?
明白吗？
So, I can't do both.
所以，我不能两者兼顾。
It means that when I talk about the ectoderm,
这意味着当我谈论外胚层时，
I will always talk to you about the ectomesoderm
我总是会谈论外中胚层
or the endomesoderm.
或内中胚层。
Okay?
明白吗？
Because they are linked, they function like that.
因为它们是相互关联的，它们就是这样运作的。
However, when I talk to you purely about the mesoderm,
然而，当我纯粹地谈论中胚层时，
I will talk to you about the mesoderm, with the mesoderm.
我将谈论中胚层与中胚层。
It's that the base of the skull, already like that,
颅底本身就是这样，
is a balance between my neurocranium and my viscerocranium.
它是我的神经颅和我的脏颅之间的平衡。
I have mesoderm, that is to say, I have cartilaginous tissue and then bone tissue.
我有中胚层，也就是说我有软骨组织和骨组织。
The ectoblast will give all the nervous tissue and the skin.
外胚层将形成所有的神经组织和皮肤。
The mesoblast will give you everything that is skeletal, muscles, connective tissues, circulatory systems.
中胚层将形成所有的骨骼、肌肉、结缔组织、循环系统，
and everything that is
以及所有
renal or urogenital,
肾脏或泌尿生殖系统，
everything that is endoblast,
所有内胚层，
all the digestive glands,
所有消化腺，
all the digestive epithelium and all the epithelium
所有消化上皮和所有呼吸道
respiratory.
上皮。
Your respiratory system,
你的呼吸系统，
is actually endoderm.
实际上是内胚层。
It's the same tissue as the
它与消化
digestive tissue, at the original level.
组织在原始层面是相同的组织。
And they support each other
它们在功能上
completely in
完全相互
their function. In other
支持。换句话说，一个人不会重新
words, a man does not take back
脏颅人，它对应于外胚层，或者它对应于上皮
The viscerocranial man corresponds to the ectoderm, or to the epithelial
组织，或者边界组织。
tissue, or to the boundary tissue.
脏颅人，它是内胚层，所以它是整个消化系统，它是
The viscerocranial man is the endoderm, so it's the entire digestive system, it's
整个上皮系统。
And the internal man, the mesodermal type man, corresponds to the entire
而内在的人，中胚层类型的人，对应着所有的
support system, the entire bone system,
支持系统，所有的骨骼系统，
the entire musculoskeletal system, the entire system.
所有的肌肉骨骼系统，所有的系统。
the urogenital, the entire internal circulatory system.
泌尿生殖系统，所有内部循环系统。
The support tissue, that means the interior tissue,
支持组织，意味着内部组织，
the tissue that informs the body.
塑造身体的组织。
So we will see that we can define the embryo in terms of days.
所以我们会看到，我们可以用天数来定义胚胎。
We can also talk about Carnegie stages.
我们也可以谈论卡内基。
I will talk to you in days.
我将按天数告诉你们。
When there are synchronicities of phenomena,
当现象同步发生时，
like the closure of the neuropores,
比如神经孔的闭合，
with the integration of these somites and things like that,
伴随着这些叶片和其他事物的整合，
we would give you the time.
我们会告诉你们时间。
At the moment of the heart's awakening,
在心脏意识觉醒的时候，
we would give precise points.
我们会给出精确的时间点。
Otherwise, we will talk about days or weeks.
否则，我们会谈论天或周。
And also, we will give some notions of size.
我们还会给出一些大小的概念。
What is really important for you,
对你们来说真正重要的是，
is the notion of growth.
是生长的概念。
It's to see that it grows.
是看到它在成长。
In fact, what you need to understand,
事实上，需要理解的是，
is that it's a developmental movement.
这是一种发展运动。
In learning.
在学习中。
It's a movement that develops like that, but it's not a movement that happens
这是一种这样发展的运动，但它不是一种
like that.
这样的运动。
That's the difference between what we call motility and mobility.
这就是我们所说的自发性运动（motility）和活动性运动（mobility）之间的区别。
One is an embryonic response, that is to say, it follows the movement of
一个是胚胎反应，也就是说它遵循
development,
发展运动，
and the other is a movement purely linked to
而另一个是纯粹与
respiration and which will give movements,
呼吸相关的运动，它会产生运动，
and the other is a movement still given to motor skills.
而另一个是与运动功能相关的运动。
You see, you have to make a clear distinction. When I move like this, it's very different from
你看，必须很好地区分。当我这样移动时，这与
the movement at the level of my liver.
我肝脏的运动非常不同。
So if I want to rework a tissue, I give it back its motility.
所以如果我想重新处理一个组织，我会在其自发性运动中重新赋予它。
And its functional strength is there. You see, it's
而它的功能力量就在那里。你看，
there where it will resume.
它会从那里恢复。
And that's the work we do, it's to go back into this tissue so that it, okay, I reorganize myself and
这就是我们所做的工作，回到这个组织中，让它，好的，我重新组织，然后
there I can regain my mobility, my motor skills.
我就可以找回我的活动性，我的运动功能。
Do you understand?
你明白吗？
It's always about following the movement,
总是跟随运动，
but here, you need the fulcrums
但在这里，你需要支点
and to have the movement in your hand.
并将运动掌握在手中。
I don't treat an organ.
我不治疗一个器官。
I treat an environment.
我治疗一个环境。
But sometimes, my action can be on
但有时，我的行动可能作用于
mobility, motor skills.
活动性、运动性。
And there, in mobility, what is it?
那么，在活动性中，它是什么？
The master of mobility is the diaphragm.
活动性的主宰是膈肌。
That's why we're going to learn how this diaphragm is built.
这就是为什么我们将学习膈肌是如何形成的。
One day, he taught me, he said, Marc, one day, you will feel the power in the tissue.
有一天，他教导我，他说，马克，有一天，你会感受到组织中的力量。
For me, power was very intellectual.
对我来说，力量是非常理性的。
At the same time, intellectually, I tell myself, yes, I can understand that there is a kind of.
同时，理性地，我想，是的，我能理解有一种。
I see an embryo developing, you can imagine the power of the thing.
我看到一个胚胎在发育，你能想象那东西的力量吗？
It doesn't stop.
它永不停歇。
There's a power, it's crazy.
有一种力量，太疯狂了。
And he tells me, sometimes,
他说，有时，
In the stimuli, in certain fulcrums, the power is there too, you see, and then, there, you can, something
在刺激中，在某些支点中，力量也存在，你看，女士，在那里，你可以，它
happens, but you can't create that all the time.
发生了一些事情，但你不能一直创造它。
You have to try to be present, to have a good connection, and then at some point, the system
你必须努力让自己处于当下，保持良好的连接，然后在一个特定的时刻，系统会
adjusts, you see.
调整，你看。
And then, at some point, he tells me, well, it's as if you were on a small boat in the sea, you see, you
然后，在某个时刻，他对我说，看，这就像你在一艘小船上，在大海里，你看，你
were just in the water, like that, you see.
只是在水里，就这样，你看。
You don't see it, but beneath you, a whale is coming.
你看不见它，但在你下面，有一头鲸鱼来了。
And you're just there and you feel it.
而你，你就在那里，你感受着。
You feel it all of a sudden.
你突然感受到了。
It's a bit like that sensation.
有点像那种感觉。
But look,
但是看，
first day,
第一天，
the little mess that we are,
我们这个小小的混乱，
and look what will happen
看看会发生什么
at the end of the second month.
在第二个月底。
Look in two months,
看看两个月内，
already what is happening.
已经发生了什么。
And look already here,
再看看这里，
beginning of the twentieth day,
第二十天开始，
a form is already being made.
已经形成了一个形状。
Here, the potential for life is there.
生命潜力就在那里。
This is simply an ovum that has received the genetic heritage
这只是一个卵子，它接收了父亲的
of the father,
遗传物质，
so the sperm, and the two heritages are busy meeting.
也就是精子，这两种遗传物质正在相互融合。
This is pretty much the first image of your life.
这大约是你生命中的第一个图像。
This is what is still called the zona pellucida and nurse cells.
这仍然被称为透明带和滋养细胞。
Another important layer of cells.
又一层重要的细胞。
If I take a cell,
如果我取一个细胞，
and I put my nucleus in the center of the cell, right in the center,
我把细胞核放在细胞的中心，正中央，
it is not polarized.
它就没有极性。
I must exchange with whom? With my environment.
我必须和谁交换？和我的环境。
I must exchange with you.
我必须和你交换。
Well, if I create here, there, I create a possibility of exchange
嗯，如果我在这里创造，在那里，我创造了一个交换的可能性
the same for my entire environment.
我的整个环境也是如此。
However, one image, and that's why, remember,
另一方面，一个图像，这就是为什么，请记住，
in a cell,
在一个细胞中，
In all the cells of your body, the nucleus
在你身体的所有细胞中，细胞核
is never in the center.
从不在中心。
It is always eccentric.
它总是偏心的。
And that is the momentary image of a polarity.
这就是极性的瞬间图像。
Why? Because if I have a cell here with an eccentric nucleus,
为什么？因为如果我这里有一个细胞，细胞核
eccentric,
偏心，
I have a much more important metabolic activity
我这里的代谢活动要大得多。
here.
这里。
And I must have...
我必须有...
this field of activity
这个活动领域
more important, it increases
更重要，它增加了
the metabolic force.
代谢力。
And that is the expression
这就是表达
of polarity.
极性。
You see?
你明白吗？
We resume at the stage where I am an oocyte.
我们回到我是卵母细胞的阶段。
We saw that it had been
我们看到它已经被
polarized by
极化了
small cells around it
周围的小细胞
that had released things, you see,
它们释放了一些东西，你明白吗？
that had created what is called Wolpert's flag,
它们创造了所谓的沃尔珀旗，
do you remember?
你还记得吗？
Which had created concentrations
它们创造了浓度
molecular within the very
分子在其中
atomic, within my very system
原子，在我系统内部
which makes it polarized.
这使得它具有极性。
So there is a force, there is a plus,
所以有一股力量，有一个正极，
there is a minus.
有一个负极。
The sperm, when it arrives,
当精子到达时，
it comes
它会
to touch the membrane.
接触细胞膜。
We will see in detail, it releases
我们将详细探讨，它会释放
a hormone called ZP3
一种叫做 ZP3 的激素
which is a very specific thing,
这是一个非常特殊的东西，
but very interesting to know
但对于以后来说非常值得了解
for later.
。
My polarity which is here, inside the embryo, which was
我胚胎内部的极性，它在那里，
there, it's as if I had a compass, with my north and my south, you see.
就像我有一个指南针，有我的北和南，你明白吗。
Except I don't know where north and south are.
只是我不知道北和南在哪里。
It is not oriented in relation to my environment, it is oriented
它不是相对于我的环境定向的，它是相对于
in relation to my space.
我的空间定向的。
And at the moment the sperm arrives, there is a global reorganization of the parametric system
当精子到达时，系统会发生整体重组
parametric.
参数。
to space. The electric field reorganizes itself in relation to this level.
到空间。电场相对于这个水平重新组织。
It receives a
它接收到
membrane information, there is a cortical degranulation that occurs inside, so
膜信息，内部发生皮质脱颗粒，以便
that only one passes. It's an extraordinary encounter, you see,
只有一个能通过。这是一次非凡的相遇，你明白吗，
between
在
these two heritages, you see, these two movements. It's always a miracle, you see. And
这两个遗产之间，你明白吗，这两个运动。每一次都是一个奇迹，你明白吗。然后
there, all of a sudden, my oocyte is polarized and...
突然间，我的卵母细胞被极化了，然后……
the meeting of my two heritages will be created.
我的两个遗产将会相遇。
This will form a nucleus, a field.
它将形成一个细胞核，一个场。
And the nucleus, if you will, is on the, so to speak, electrical axis of the system.
如果你愿意，细胞核位于系统的“电”轴上。
But it corresponds to the fact that it is eccentric.
但它对应于它偏离中心的事实。
It's its response to globality.
这是它对整体的反应。
Now, where is the largest electrical field in our body?
现在，我们身体中最大的电场在哪里？
It's along our spinal column.
它沿着我们的脊柱。
this is a power
这是一种力量
from my brain there is a very powerful electric field
从我的大脑中有一个非常强大的电场
there is a large electric field at the heart level
心脏区域有一个强大的电场
there is a large electric field here
这里有一个强大的电场
but the most important axis is along my spinal column
但最重要的轴是沿着我的脊柱
it's a place of exchange
这是一个交流场所
very important right down to your fingertips
非常重要，直到你的指尖
but there is a concentration
但有一个集中
so we're going to do a practice
所以我们将进行一次练习
and we're going to imagine
我们将想象
that we are just a cell
我们只是一个细胞
on the table
在桌子上
And we, we're going to come, we're not going to do much.
我们不会做太多。
You're just going to put yourself.
你只需要简单地站着。
One of them will just put themselves at the foot.
其中一个人会简单地站在脚边。
You see?
你明白吗？
Either you go over there, you go a little further down, here.
你可以站在那里，再往下一点，在这里。
So someone sits here, but we don't care how we touch.
所以有人站在这里，但我们不在乎怎么触摸。
The only thing is that we touch.
唯一重要的是我们触摸。
You can touch here.
你可以触摸这里。
The only thing is that we touch gently.
唯一重要的是我们轻轻地触摸。
You, you sit there, you take a chair.
你站在那里，拿把椅子。
You, you take a chair, you sit here.
你拿把椅子，坐在这里。
And we will see in embryology that we start from
我们将在胚胎学中看到，我们从
there and we come back there.
那里开始，然后回到那里。
It's as if, at some point, we're going to leave, we're in the void,
就好像，在某个时刻，我们要出发，我们处于虚空中，
and then all of a sudden, we're going to be attached by a thread like that, in the universe, you see, in the universe of the
然后突然，我们会像这样被一根线连接起来，在宇宙中，你明白，在
sea.
海洋的宇宙中。
And then everything will develop, everything will come back around, like that.
然后一切都会发展，一切都会像这样围绕着回来。
We go from a pellicle to a cord.
我们从薄膜走向脐带。
Everything integrates like this.
一切都这样整合。
The navel is always in the right place.
肚脐总是在正确的位置。
Sometimes, it's us who are not in the right place.
有时，是我们没有在正确的位置。
We're not going to try to do anything like that, no.
我们不会尝试做任何这样的事情，不。
We come back to all this.
我们回到这一切。
Because he is connected with,
因为他与
we call the anterior sky, the posterior sky,
我们称之为前天、后天
and everything I mean.
以及我想说的一切相连。
We're just going to, by putting ourselves there,
我们只是，通过站在那里，
simply put ourselves on this reference
简单地将自己置于这个参照点
and let's see how the body organizes itself.
并让身体自己组织。
You know, you will have to learn to recognize in practice, all of a sudden, all of a sudden, a process can be established.
你们知道，在实践中，你们必须学会识别，突然之间，突然之间，一个过程可能会
be established.
建立起来。
And that, you have to accompany it, because it's health that starts to work.
这需要我们去配合，因为这是健康开始发挥作用。
You have to accompany it.
我们必须配合它。
We are hypnotized by the eyes.
我们被眼睛催眠了。
We are attracted by this, attracted by that.
我们被这个吸引，被那个吸引。
And there, I propose to you, in the work we are going to do with embryology, this biodynamic
在这里，我向你们建议，在我们将在胚胎学中进行的这项工作中，这种生物动力学
it's...
是...
I saw you, but I'm not leaving with you.
我看到你了，但我不会和你一起走。
I recognize, no, no, I saw you, I saw you, but I stay on health.
我承认，不，不，我看到你了，我看到你了，但我坚持健康。
I remain in the dynamic of health.
我坚持健康的动态。
I am on the health fulcrum.
我全身心投入健康。
I stay on it.
我坚持下去。
I would like to share a short film by an Aikido master with you.
我想和你们分享一部关于一位合气道大师的小电影。
There are two, three little things.
有两三件小事。
We talked earlier about the notion of space, the notion of unity, you
我们刚才谈到了空间的概念，统一的概念，你
see, and the notion of globality.
看，还有整体性的概念。
the notion also
还有和谐的概念
a little bit
一点点
of harmony
和谐
of things like that
诸如此类
you make a gesture
你做一个手势
it's that
那就是
you take a baby
你抱一个婴儿
I explain
我解释一下
as if you were taking
就像你抱起
in fact you take a space
实际上你占据了一个空间
you don't take a baby like that
你不是这样抱婴儿的
you take a baby like that
你是这样抱婴儿的
You really take up all the space.
你真的占据了所有的空间。
What I want to open up to you is this notion of space.
我想向你们展示的是空间的概念。
Because we're going to work with points of silence.
因为我们将使用静止点进行工作。
We're going to look for fulcrums in the body.
我们将在身体中寻找支撑点。
But there are different depths in the silence that need to be laid down.
但在需要平息的寂静中，有不同的深度。
There is a silence where there are first ones,
有一种寂静，那里有最初的，
and then there are deeper and deeper silences,
然后有越来越深的寂静，
which are also connected to spaces.
它们也与空间相关联。
It's as if we're going to have to...
这就像我们必须...
become aware of the space of the body
意识到身体的空间
become aware of the space, of this energy
意识到空间，这种能量
that is a bit around me
它在我周围
become aware of the room
意识到房间
also become aware
也要意识到
really of space
真正的空间
and if we manage little by little
如果我们一点一点地达到
to this depth
这个深度
you will see that there are qualities
你会看到有一些品质
is that said?
这是这样说的吗？
qualities of silence
寂静的品质
that are different
它们是不同的
and we will try little by little
我们将尝试一点一点地
in the work that we will gradually
在我们即将一点一点地
start doing together,
开始一起做的工作中，
to go and find this quality of silence.
去寻找那种寂静的品质。
Because the body needs
因为身体需要
this fulcrum,
这个支点，
this point of silence
这个寂静点
to bring about a transformation.
才能产生转变。
It's easy English.
这在英语中很容易。
What is he doing there?
他在这里做什么？
He brings his consciousness, his mind, into his center of gravity.
他将他的意识、他的心智带回到他的重心。
So he's there, he even makes an upward movement.
所以他在这里，他甚至做了一个向上的动作。
He feels his energy here.
他在这里感受到他的能量。
it's an important energy center
这是一个重要的能量中心
we will also see it purely on a biological level, we have the spirit
我们也会看到，即使在
that gathers this energy here
这种能量聚集在这里
he refocuses
他重新集中
in his vital energy
在他的生命能量中
Thank you.
谢谢。
who have no idea what you're trying to give them.
他们对你试图给予他们的东西一无所知。
Is it possible to take a group of them
是否有可能召集一群人
and present them with this totally different sense of
并向他们展示这种完全不同的
values?
价值观？
Is it possible?
这可能吗？
First, we make sure that non-fighting is not avoiding fighting.
首先，我们确保不打架不是避免打架。
Suppose violence comes this way, if you go
假设暴力以这种方式到来，如果你走
that way, you are avoiding, whereas if
那条路，你是在逃避，而如果
you
你
go opposite.
走向相反。
you will resist.
你会抵抗。
So non-fighting
所以不打架
is that you don't have to avoid,
就是你不需要避免，
you don't have to resist,
你不需要抵抗，
so how can you do it?
那么你该怎么做呢？
You should know
你应该知道
how you stay where you are.
你如何保持你所在的位置。
You are here,
你在这里，
you stay where you are.
你保持你所在的位置。
And how do you do it?
你是怎么做到的？
You do it with this perception
你用这种感知
of space.
空间。
That's a bit.
这有点。
and he remains without the actor
他没有留下任何痕迹
okay, try the sharing
好的，尝试分享
when I lay him down, I am seeing
当我躺下时，我正在看着自己
and I see the time of the actor
我看到了演员的时间
and this time of the actor
而这个演员的时间
it's the correct one
这是正确的
and then
然后
And if you want more, you do this.
如果你想要更多，你就这样做。
So every time you stop.
所以每次你停下来。
Okay, you stopped.
好的，你停下来了。
And you stopped.
你停下来了。
It's stopped.
它停下来了。
Okay, so...
好的，那么...
You stopped.
你停下来了。
So each time you try to stop
所以每次你尝试停止
with perception.
用感知。
Now next, you must know how to move without
现在接下来，你必须知道如何在不
moving.
移动的情况下移动。
This means that you are the body without being
这意味着你就是身体，而你
the brain.
就是大脑。
And here, it means that you are the brain in space.
在这里，这意味着你就是空间中的大脑。
You are here, in space.
你在这里，在空间中。
So, this perception of space cannot move.
所以，这种对空间的感知是不能移动的。
So, it's here.
所以，它在这里。
So, this means that you are the brain.
所以，这意味着你就是大脑。
So I don't stop, I don't stop here, and now I'm
所以我不会停下来，我不会在这里停下来，现在我
just going to keep this space.
只会保持这个空间。
Which means there's no fighting.
这意味着没有战斗。
If we are there, if we are there, if we are there, it is fighting.
如果我们在这里，如果我们在这里，如果我们在这里，那就是战斗。
If we are there, it is there, it is there, it is there.
如果我们在这里，它就在这里，它就在这里，它就在这里。
This space does not stop.
这个空间不会停止。
It's true, it's true.
这是真的，这是真的。
Subtitling
字幕
ST' 501
ST' 501
I cannot move others without
我不能在不移动他人的情况下
moving others.
移动他人。
Okay, so we're going to practice.
好的，所以我们要练习。
If I want to move his body, maybe I can.
如果我想移动他的身体，也许我可以。
But he can't move.
但他不能动。
So now, I'm going to move the others.
所以现在，我要移动其他人。
Moving means there's a space in which his body is, okay,
移动意味着他的身体所处的空间，好的，
and so move the space without moving his body, okay, that
所以移动空间而不移动他的身体，好的，那
means here, just take the space, this
意味着这里，只是占据空间，这
is move others without moving, okay, that's all right.
是在不移动的情况下移动他人，好的，没关系。
You have something up there?
你上面有什么吗？
Now, if I'm going to go to the next slide, I'm going to go to the next slide.
现在，如果我要去下一张幻灯片，我要去下一张幻灯片。
If I want to turn you like this, it becomes conflict.
如果我希望你这样转动，就会产生冲突。
So, like a baby, there is a space, and I take all of the space.
所以，就像一个婴儿，有一个空间，我占据了整个空间。
So, that means the baby doesn't turn, just all
所以，这意味着婴儿不会转动，只是整个
of the space.
空间。
That's what you do when you baby them.
你抱婴儿的时候就是这样做的。
Babies don't turn like that.
婴儿不会这样转动。
I see that.
我明白了。
So you can do that even with others?
所以你甚至可以对其他人这样做？
...
...
Thank you.
谢谢。
It's easier, isn't it?
这更容易，不是吗？
Yes, it's easier.
是的，这更容易。
Subtitles by Radio-Canada
加拿大广播公司字幕
How can we move without destroying?
我们如何在不破坏的情况下移动？
So, if we move space, we can move this person
所以，如果我们移动空间，我们就可以
with respect.
尊重地移动这个人。
That is to say, we do not destroy this person.
也就是说，我们不会破坏这个人。
So, this is Aikido.
所以，这就是合气道。
In Aikido, you should treat all people, in all circumstances, with respect.
在合气道中，你应该在所有情况下都尊重所有人。
When people are in love, they say "Oh, hello!"
当人们相爱时，他们会说“哦，你好！”
But when there are people who are not in love, they start
但是当有些人不相爱时，他们就会开始
to fight against relationships.
与关系作斗争。
That is to say, they do not maintain relationships with others in all circumstances.
也就是说，他们在所有情况下都不会与他人保持关系。
So, both hands.
所以，双手。
If I want him to be from him, he is from him, there is no respect.
如果我希望有他，就有他，没有尊重。
So, there is a space here.
所以，这里有一个空间。
There is a space here.
这里有一个空间。
It's good, it's good, it's
好的，好的，好的。
good.
好的。
Yes, it's good.
是的，好的。
Let's go, let's go.
开始了，开始了。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
So...
所以...
I see.
我明白了。
Yes, that's it.
是的，就是这样。
Okay, that's it.
好的，就是这样。
I'm going to put you behind.
我把你放在后面。
Let's go.
开始了。
Okay, try.
好的，试试。
Try.
试试。
An axis, a cattle.
一个轴，一个牲畜。
I have a first zone.
我有一个第一个区域。
A first zone that can respond to the body.
一个可以响应身体的第一个区域。
We'll say to the physical body.
我们称之为物理身体。
First zone.
第一个区域。
To zone A.
区域A。
And then around you, you emit a radiation,
然后，在你周围，你散发出一种辐射，
a warmth, a space around
一种热量，你周围的一个空间。
you.
在你周围。
And then there's the room you're in, and
然后是你所在的房间，然后是地平线。
then there's the horizon.
然后是地平线。
we're going to look for
我们将去寻找
in each space, little by little, we'll start from the beginning
在每个空间中，一点一点地，我们将从头开始
to find this point of silence, when I enter a room
找回那个寂静点，当我进入一个房间时
very quickly I look for how I position myself in this room
我很快就会寻找我如何在这个房间里定位自己
how the space around me is, how I can position myself
我周围的空间如何，我如何定位自己
to be well, me in the practice of embryology that we are going to do
才能感觉良好，我在我们将要进行的胚胎学实践中
we will work with these spaces, the body will reorient itself
我们将利用这些空间，身体将重新定位
in relation to this space. The space is there. It's just about being in adequacy.
相对于这个空间。空间就在那里。这只是一个适应的问题。